A Guide to the Papers of Allen Ginsberg 1960-1963
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Allen Ginsberg 1960-1963
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
7883
12 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Biographical/Historical Information
American poet, 1926- and leader of the Beat movement.
Scope and Content Information
The collection consists of 12 postcards and brief letters to Lucien and Francesca Carr.
Arrangement
Chronological order.
Contents List
- Allen Ginsberg to Lucien Carr 1960 February 16, APCS
  Describes Valdivia, Chile, and experiences there with Peter Orlovsky at the university, and future travel plans in South America.
- Allen Ginsberg to Lucien and Francesca Carr 1961 May 27, APCS
  Describes experiences in Cannes, the film crew working on The Connection, St. Tropez, plans for travel to Marseilles and Tangier to see William Burroughs.
- Allen Ginsberg to Lucien Carr 1961 July 28, TLS w/envelope, 1 p.
  Discusses invasion of Cuba, William Burroughs, The Soft Machine, travel in France and Morocco, plans for travel in Israel and India, Jack Kerouac.
- Allen Ginsberg to Lucien and Francesca Carr 1962 May 16, TLS w/envelope, 1 p.
  Describes experiences in India, temples, poets, actors, Tibetan tankas, music. Mentions Epics, Myths and Legends of India by Paul Thomas.
- Allen Ginsberg to Lucien and Francesca Carr 1962 July 28, TLS 1 p.
  Describes Tibetan pictures being sent for safekeeping, travels in India, monasteries, life in Calcutta, Bengali poets, mutual friends including Jack Kerouac and William Burroughs.
- Allen Ginsberg to Lucien and Francesca Carr 1962 October 6, TLS 2 p.
  Describes Durga puja, a religious holiday being celebrated in Calcutta, and other rituals. Discusses publication of Reality Sandwiches, correspondence with Bertrand Russell concerning fears of nuclear holocaust, future travel plans, and Bengali poets.
- Allen Ginsberg to Lucien and Francesca Carr 1962 November 3, TLS 1 p.
  Discusses controversial poem, Bertrand Russell's fear of nuclear danger and other current political matters, visit to a monastery in Bengal, plans to attend religious and musical festivals and more travel.
- Allen Ginsberg to Francesca Carr 1962 November 16, ALS 1 p.
  Inquires about Tibetan paintings, describes experiences in Calcutta, and Indian music.
- Allen Ginsberg to Lucien and Francesca Carr [1963 January 15?], TLS 1 p.
  Describes surroundings and experiences in Benares, India, and the Taj Mahal, writing projects, current state of the Cold War, and India's war with China.
- Allen Ginsberg to Lucien and Francesca Carr 1963 August 19, APCS
  Briefly describes activities in Vancouver while teaching students and sense of satisfaction about India experience.
- Allen Ginsberg to Lucien and Francesca Carr 1963 November 22, TPCS
  Describes plan to return to Paterson, N.J., for family visit, and current state of mind.
- Allen Ginsberg to Lucien and Francesca Carr [n.y.] October 6, APCS
  Discusses plans to visit Israel and India, requests William Burroughs' address and news of Harvard.